

# **ABOUT ME**

Solution-driven Web Developer adept at contributing to highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions and determining customer satisfaction. Proven experience developing consumer focused websites using HTML, CSS, Node-JS and JavaScript. Built products for desktop and mobile app users over 3.5+ years, meeting highest standards for web design, user experience, best practices and speed. Designed and developed web applications across multiple APIs, third-party integrations and databases.

#### **LANGUAGES**

**ENGLISH** 

KISWAHILI

#### **LINKS**

GitHub
github.com/eugenesang

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/eugenesang

Portfolio <u>eugene-sang.web.app</u>

# EUGENE SANG

**FULL STACK DEVELOPER** 





eugeneksang@gmail.com



+254 718 925 969

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# TRUSTED ADVISERS REALTY

Edmonton - Canada

Present

#### Fullstack Web Developer (Remote)

CTO and Fullstack developer

Oversaw development and maintenance of live realty site

Implemented technologies for dynamic, responsive functionality

Led creation of in-house automation software for efficiency

Managed remote work effectively from Kenya for a Canadian company

# WORKHUB WRITERS

Nairobi - Kenya

Feb 2023 - present

# Fullstack Web Developer

Served as CTO, led website design and user needs analysis

Built website using HTML, CSS, AJAX, and React

Managed back-end operations using NodeJS, MongoDB, Express

Incorporated payment system using PayPal, M-Pesa APIs

#### **STOCKISHA**

Nairobi - Kenya

May 2023 - Aug 2023

#### **Backend Developer**

Spearheaded user-focused designs at Stockisha.com

Exploited HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, JSON, React for smooth functionality

Boosted operations and security via NodeJS, MongoDB

Optimized payment flow with M-Pesa, PayPal API integration

## TOP ESSAY INC.

Nairobi - Kenya

Dec 2021 - May 2022

#### **Fullstack Web Developer**

Transformed mockups into engaging web presence with HTML, JavaScript, AJAX

Engineered server and API endpoints using Node.js for site functionality

Integrated Flutter wave payment system for superior user convenience

Effectively juggled front-end development and database administration duties

# **EDUCATION**

## SOUTH EASTERN KENYA UNIVERSITY

Kitui - Kenya

Sep 2019 - Aug 2023

#### **Bachelor of Science - Education**

Majored in Mathematics and Physics

Excelled in rigorous tests to earn Bsc. Maths & Physics

Joined tech communities to practice my teaching, problem solving and software engineering skills

#### BARTOLIMO BOYS' HIGH SCHOOL

Baringo - Kenya

Feb 2015 - Nov 2018

### Kenya Secondary Education

Excelled in Mathematics, Sciences and Computer studies

Exceeded the minimum requirement to join University

Awarded the Kenya Certificate of Secondary education by the Kenya National Examination Council

## BISHOP MUGE ACADEMY -KAMOGOIWO

Nandi - Kenya

2007 - Nov 2014

# Kenya Primary Education

Awarded the Kenya Certificate of Primary Education by the Kenya National Examination Council

Got enough marks required to join a National level Secondary school

# **PROJECTS**

#### HARAMBEE MANAGER

**Fund Raising Management App** 

Node.js, Express, Google APIs, React, Next.js, MongoDB

# EDMONTON REAL ESTATE EXPERTS

**Real Estate Website** 

Node.js, express, MySql, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, EJS,

WORKHUB WRITERS

Freelance Writing Platform

Node.js, express, MongoDB, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, EJS,

**TOP ESSAY INC** 

Freelance Writer's Landing Page

Node.js, express, MongoDB, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, React

#### **KV MARKET**

Local Town's Marketplace

Node.js, express, MySql, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, EJS,

# **SKILLS**



JavaScript **HTML** CSS Node.js MongoDB MySql PostgresSql React.js Next.js Firebase APIs Adobe Illustrator Adobe Photoshop Figma Postman Docker Stripe PayPal M-Pesa VsCode SEO Web Apps Auth Responsive Web Design **Payment Processing** Python C++ C#